I've been using the again faster Pursuit
Olympic Bar for a few weeks now and my
favorite things about it are the super
grippy volcano style nerling the
self-lubricating bronze bushings in the
loading sleeves and then honestly just
the fact that this bar can serve as the
only barbell in your home gym I'm really
big on multi-purpose bars so I'm really
excited to break this one down for you
guys let's get right to
it
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I've got the again faster Pursuit
Olympic bar now I'm going to talk about
a whole lot of things into this camera
today but specifically we're going to
talk about some money some pros and cons
and who should or maybe should not
purchase this barbell for their home gym
but before I do all of that if you guys
aren't aware we've reviewed a ton of
barbells in bar.com and we did the hard
part for you and made a best list of all
of our top choices so if you want to
check that out all you got to do is
search barbin best barbells it's going
to pull right up for you and you can
find out for yourself which ones we like
the
best all right so let's talk about what
I like about this barbell and first
things first got to talk about the fact
that it is a multi-purpose bar despite
you know the actual title of it being
Pursuit Olympic Bar okay so don't get it
confused this is a multi-purpose bar and
the reason for that mainly is because of
the self-lubricating bronze bushings in
the loading sleeves all right so
multi-purpose bars tend to you know just
have bronze bushings they last longer
than needle bearings and ball bearings
and they're cost efficient cost
effective I guess you could say so
that's a a major thing right there but
also you have dual neural markings right
here so with a powerlifting bar or an
Olympic lifting bar you're only going to
have you know one set and so ones on the
outside are set by the international
weightlifting Federation iwf ones on the
inside are the ipf international
powerlifting Federation okay and as far
as the actual nerling goes it is sweet
I'm going be honest it uh it's got this
volcano style knurling so if you don't
know what that is each individual
marking right here on you know this
cross-hatching pattern it dips in like a
volcano right so they basically cut the
top off of them and each point is going
to give you four points of contact on
your hands so it's just going to give
you the best grip possible in my opinion
volcano style and there's a lot of
people who agree you know despite you
know texture being personal preference
and everything volcano style is the best
style and honestly this is not
aggressive but it's more on the
aggressive side of the spectrum it's not
going to tear your hands up as you go to
do some power cleans or anything like
that but you know having a little bit of
you know abrasiveness right here that it
has I think this barbell it works great
for any type of powerlifting movement
this is our best rated our best CrossFit
bar but honestly I think it really
excels with those powerlifting movements
there's also two different versions so
it's available in 15 and 20 kg which is
really nice and then it's competitively
priced which I'll expand on in just a
second now that being said there's still
some things that you might not be too
crazy about and you know the first thing
is just a fact it's not going to be the
best at any one particular lift yes you
can do you know everything with it yes
it's our best CrossFit bar I also think
it works great for powerlifting but it's
you know if you go and take you know a
dedicated power bar or an Olympic Bar
you know whatever and you you know pin
it head-to-head with one of those you
know that specialty bar is going to
outperform this bar so definitely keep
that in mind and then I want to take a
second and talk about these loading
sleeves all right so there's a little
bit of play here and I'll kind of show
you guys up close in a minute but you
know this kind of slides back into forth
and it's on both sides that's not
something that you typically see with a
barbell uh I don't notice it when I'm
actually lifting with it which is a good
thing obviously but it's definitely
something you need to be aware of and
then honestly they definitely spin the
sleeves obviously Spin and you know it
it works well as you're lifting with it
but they don't spin as freely you know
as quickly and everything as some other
barbells that I've reviewed so just two
things that you definitely want to be
aware
of
[Music]
okay so let's talk about some money now
with this barbell and so the 15 kg
version that's going to run you right
around 270 while the 20 kg version
that's about 285 honestly it's really
competitively price I think it's a you
know a nice approachable price tag and
it's pretty solid you know compared to
the rest of the market you know a bar
that I'm really high on is the living
fit barbell the Chrome version is going
to run you 200 bucks you know and the
specs are very similar here so you know
if you want to save $85 might not be
that big of a deal you know but still 85
bucks you'd be surprised what you can do
with it so you want to save that money
that's a really solid option and then
also you know there's other barbells
there's plenty of barbells that are more
expensive than this another one that I
like a lot is the rep Fitness Colorado
bar that Chrome version is going to run
you around 320 bucks so you know all in
all it's about you know average I guess
you could say and then obviously you
know you've got other bars like the
Rogue Ohio bar that you know it's going
to cost you at least 370 bucks if you
want to go for stainless steel there's
some other ones that are going to be you
know5 $20 more than this one right here
so you know at the end of the day you
know I think the way it performs I think
the actual specs and the quality of it I
think 285 is honestly or 270 it's
honestly a pretty sweet
deal okay so let's talk about the
overall construction with this barbell
and I just you know want to mention I
forgot to mention this earlier this is a
bright zinc barbell it's the only
coating finish whatever you want to call
it that this bar is available in all
right so bright zinc it offers a decent
amount of protection from Rus and
corrosion but if you're somebody who you
know say you keep all your gear stashed
in you know just a basic garage with no
heat no air no nothing gets pretty
steamy in there you're going to want to
Target something that offers a higher
level of protection you know maybe s Co
or stainless steel those are the top two
those are the top two so that's going to
be you know better for you than bright
zinc if you do decide you know just to
keep keep it rolling with this bright
zinc then you'll just want to clean it
every once in a while maybe once or
twice a month you just get some you know
3 in-1 multi-purpose oil kind of rub it
on here with a rag take a nylon brush
get all the junk out of here just to you
know clean it up the right way now the
15 kg bar is 79 in long with 13-inch
loading sleeves and a diameter of 25 mm
while this 20 KG Bar 86 in long with 16
1/2 in loading sleeve sleaves and it's
28 mm in diameter remember you do have
this volcano style nerling it's honestly
it's pretty it's pretty deep the way
it's cut so you're getting a really
really nice grip right here I you know
yes this is listed our best CrossFit bar
I personally enjoy it better for my
powerlifting movements because of how
good of a grip I'm able to get right
here you remember you do have your dual
dual neural markings right here and this
bar also has a tensil strength rating of
190,000 PSI so if you don't know what
tensil strength is that's literally
going to tell you how strong a barbell
is and how much force how much weight it
can handle before it begins to you know
lose its original shape all right so
190k that's a really solid number for
the majority of athletes but especially
for anybody who's going to be performing
you know dynamic lifts such as power
cleans hang cleans clean and jerk snatch
all of that stuff because if you go
higher than that you're going to start
getting less flexion less whip in the
bar and that's not something that you
want you know with an explosive movement
right so 190k that's like right in that
sweet spot right there now remember you
do have your self lubricating bronze
bushings in the loading sleeves and they
they produce a pretty solid rate of spin
I'll I'll show you guys again in just a
second and then you do have you know a
grooved pattern right here on the
loading sleeves themselves and that's
designed to help keep your weight plates
in their original placement so whenever
you're doing you know deadlifts or any
other lift where the bar is repeatedly
being dropped on the ground those plates
are going to slide down the sleeve but
you know those grooves are designed to
help keep them there end of the day
though you definitely still want to use
some weight
[Music]
collar all right so remember with this
bar you do have a Groove pattern right
here you know these grooves these ridges
whatever you want to call them they're
really beneficial and they're going to
help keep those weight plates at least
in some way help keep them from sliding
down and sliding off kind of making your
your lift unbalanced something that you
don't want now remember you do have self
lubricating bronze bushings in your
sleeves right here to create that spin
and self lubricating if you don't know
it's literally exactly how it sounds
they're going to lubricate themselves
you don't have to do anything you don't
have to take the sleeve apart so that's
nice if you don't want to take all those
extra steps now you do have a little bit
of play right here as I mentioned
earlier with this sleeve and I'm going
to show you this kind of leads to the
Clank that I've noticed with this bar
it's kind of loud especially when you
drop it okay so as we move in I I can't
stop talking about it I really do really
really really do like this nerling it's
some of the best nerling I've felt on a
barbell in a while especially with a
zinc bar you know any bar that's Co
tends to be a little bit slippery and
honestly this feels almost like a
stainless steel or a bare steel bar I
mean the grip is not compromised at all
and that's a sweet thing you do have
your dual neural markings right here iwf
ipf it's pretty much the standard with
all multi-purpose bars cuz you're doing
you're able to do any type of lift and
then you know this is a zinc bar
remember that it's prone to get you know
some type of rust and corrosion built up
over time I'm talking you know a year
you're going to notice some stuff if you
don't clean it at all you're going to
notice some buildup but maybe sooner
kind of just depends but if you do you
know take the proper precautions you're
really not going to notice anything at
all and then I really like how there's
no Center NE right here I really like
that with my barbell
it's just more comfortable on your skin
whenever you're lifting now I want to
take one quick second throw some weight
on here and I'm going to do a little
drop test and show you guys you know the
actual noise level with this barbell so
hang
[Music]
on all right here we
go that's pretty loud all right now I've
got this living fit bar I'm going to
just do a little comparison
with
I'll do it one more time I'll do it one
more time here I'll start with this one
again all right all
right that's pretty loud you know so if
you have neighbors nearby you don't want
to be that obnoxious neighbor who's
making a bunch of noise at you know the
worst possible time of the day
definitely keep that in mind with this
barbell right here so if you're somebody
looking for a 15 kg bar I think this is
a really solid place for you to start
your search now also if you're looking
for a multi-purpose bar you know to
handle all of your lifts I really think
this is a really good option too you
know yes this is ranked as our best
CrossFit bar it excels in those kind of
lifts but I also personally really enjoy
using it for my power lifts and
especially because of the volcano style
nerling right here I mean it feels
really really good in my hands and it
just gives me an awesome grip and that's
something that you definitely want you
never want your grip to be compromised
so you know like I said if you're
looking for a bar to you know handle all
of your lifts this one definitely you
know fits the bill on the flip side the
bright zinc finish right here might not
be the best for everybody yes it offers
you know a decent amount of protection
from rust and corrosion but not really
you know you know the top with stainless
steel and serak Coe so if you're not in
a climate controlled room you might want
to you know go find yourself you know a
different coated barbell or just you
know spend some more time take care of
it more and and clean it and then also
just remember
just because it can handle all the lifts
doesn't mean it's the best at any one
particular lift that's the case with all
multi-purpose bars so it kind of just
you it is what it is it's something that
you'll just have to deal with it's still
going to handle everything great just
not as well as a you know specialty bar
wood so keep that in mind too and then
remember you know as I mentioned and and
showed you guys this is a pretty clanky
barbell it's pretty noisy yes all
barbells are going to make noise when
you drop them repeatedly but this is one
of the louder bars that you know i' I've
used lately and if you have you know
close by neighbors and you don't want to
be that neighbor then you might want to
consider a different
[Music]
bar well that's all I got for y'all
today on the again faster Pursuit
Olympic Bar I really like this bar it's
competitively priced it can handle all
of your lifts but remember right zinc
may not be the best for everybody and
it's a bit noisy when you drop it
repeatedly thanks for hanging out with
yall I hope this video was really
helpful and I was able to tell you
everything you need to know about this
barbell I say it all the time and
nobody's going to stop me stay on the
lookout for my next video but for now
head over to barb. comom because we have
a full written article about this
barbell that you absolutely should check
out all you got to do is search barbend
again faster Pursuit Olympic barbell
review it's going to pull right up for
you you can go over every single thing
we talked about here today I'll catch
youall next
time
[Music]
oh